ryanair.com 2014-12-12

# Privacy Policy | Your Data

Ryanair is committed to protecting your privacy, our website Privacy Statement sets out what information we collect, how we collect it, what we do with it and how we protect this information.

### Personal Data

In order to process your booking, we collect personal details from you. These details may include (where applicable) passenger names, addresses, passport or Government issued EU National ID card numbers, telephone numbers, e-mail and IP addresses, credit/debit card or other payment details. In some instances we may also collect information regarding medical conditions (only for passengers who have special medical requirements) which may affect the chosen flight arrangements.

Your data may be used for the following purposes: contacting you in the event of a flight time change or cancellation, credit or other payment card verification/screening, immigration/customs control safety, security, health, administrative, crime prevention/detection, legal purposes, statistical and marketing analysis, systems testing, customer surveys and customer relations communications.

We may also disclose your information to contracted companies who act as "data processors" on our behalf, or with your agreement to ancillary service providers such as hotel, car hire and credit card providers.

We follow strict security procedures in the storage and disclosure of passenger information. Our security procedures require that we request proof of identity before we disclose sensitive information regarding your flight reservation.

### Direct Marketing Material

From time to time we may contact you with information regarding flight promotions and ancillary products via email. However, you will have the choice to opt in or out of receiving such communications by indicating so at booking stage. You will also be given the opportunity on every e-communication that we send you to indicate that you no longer wish to receive our direct marketing material.

### Site tracking

We use tracking software to monitor customer traffic patterns and site usage to help us develop the design and layout of the websites. This software does not enable us to capture any personal passenger information.

### Cookies

This site uses cookies to enable us to improve our service to you and to provide certain features that you may find useful. Cookies are small text files that are transferred to your computer's hard drive through your web browser to enable us to recognise your browser and help us to track visitors to our site; thus enabling us to understand better the products and services that will be most suitable to you. A cookie contains your contact information and information to allow us to identify your computer when you travel around our site for the purpose of helping you accomplish your reservation. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but, if you wish, you can set your browser to prevent it from accepting cookies. The "help" portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. The cookies we use do not detect any information stored on your computers.

For more information about cookies and how to stop cookies being installed visit the following website: [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

### Links to Third Party Websites

This privacy statement only covers websites that we own and control. It does not cover links to other websites and accordingly any information collected by those parties that own and control those websites or their use of cookies. Please be aware that inpidual organizations operate their own policies regarding the use and sale of personal information and the use of cookies. If you have a concern regarding the way your personal information will be used on other sites then you are advised to read the relevant privacy statement or in the absence of such a statement on the site, contact the company concerned. Any data stored by third party websites are stored completely separately by third party.

### Security

We take great care to ensure the security of this site. The data you provide to us is protected using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) technology. SSL is the industry standard method of encrypting personal information and credit card details so that they can be securely transferred over the Internet.

### Your Rights

You have the right to ask in writing for a copy of the information we hold about you (for which we may charge a maximum fee of €6.35) and also to correct any inaccuracies in your information.

Our registered address is :  
Customer Services  
Ryanair Dublin Office  
Airside Business Park  
Swords  
Co. Dublin  
Ireland

### Changes to Privacy Statement

Our Privacy Statement may change from time to time and any changes to the statement will be posted on this page.
